Burhanuddin Ezzi

Hi, I am Burhanuddin, a Computer Science student at Habib University. In my 6-year-old passion for computers, I can undoubtedly say that I am a Computer geek. As a freshman student, I am interested in internships or voluntary work for a software-related job in any organization, where I can nurture my problem-solving and analytical skills.

K141 Al Burhan Arcade Karachi, North Nazimabad +92 332 3314750 ba09ae@gmail.com

INTERESTS

- Web Programming
- Internet Protocols and Telecom
- Genetics
- Number Theory

EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneurship Club, Habib University — Treasurer

April 2022 - PRESENT

Habib University Entrepreneurship Club aims to spread awareness of business opportunities to students and constantly work to support student startups and projects.

MJ Textiles, S.I.T.E Area — *Voluntary Internship*

June 2019 - August 2019

Gained industrial experience in various departments at the company including production, sales, transportation, and execution.

EDUCATION

Habib University, Karachi — BSc. Computer Science

September 2021 - Present HUTOPS scholar

MSB Educational Institute, Karachi — HSSC

August 2018 - April 2020

Pre-Engineering, AKU-EB

MSB Educational Institute, Karachi — *SSC*

August 2016 - May 2018

Science, AKU-EB

SKILLS

Computer Programming: 3-Can do most tasks with

some learning

2- Can do small tasks.

1-Fundamental knowledge

- Python (3/5)
- C/C++(2/5)
- SQL (1/5)
- Git (3/5)

Office tools:

- Can make presentations that look aesthetic and deliver what is important
- Can make
 outstanding
 Documents using
 WYSIWYG tools like
 Word and scripting
 tools like LaTeX

Automation

Can use/write scripts for Windows
Automation.
Automation takes care of tedious tasks like finding similar documents in a drive and increases productivity.

PROJECTS

Select Images Containing A Face From A Folder

Using face-recognition module in Python which is built on dlib.

Soduko Game — *Python*(*Algorithms*)

This game is a Data-Structures and Algorithms course's final project. The GUI is made with pygame. As the game is very common, features are being added to make the game better.

Student Database — *Python*

A project made for the introductory programming course at University. As the name suggests, the application consists of relevant features. The GUI is made with Tkinter.

VOLUNTARY WORK

Zero Food Wastage

2019 - Present

Part of a work force that saves 5000+ fresh meals from going to waste each year, by packaging and distribution.

IT help for Adults

2022

Part of an organization that volunteers for technical guidance to adults.

Creativity

Have the skills for designing social media and advertisement posts

AWARDS/APPRECIATION

Certificate of Academic Excellence (HSSC and SSC) by MSB Educational Institute

Certificate of Appreciation (Prefect 2018–19) at MSB Educational Institute

Certificate of Appreciation for organizing inter-school cricket tournament.

Runner Up Spelling Bee (Primary school) at MSB Educational Institute